

Sergei Kharin

Researcher, Agricultural Economics

- 2 November 3, 1979
- 27A Timiryazeva str. APT 189 Voronezh, Russia 394087
- **2** +7 473 253 7290
- (#) WhatsApp:+79066703266
- kharins03@gmail.com
- Russian

Social Network

 R^{G}

ResearchGate Link



Facebook Link

Languages

Russian
English
German

Digital Skills

R
Programming languages
(Python and R program)
Gretl
Microsoft Office

Academic ID

Y Zoom, MS Teams

- Google Scholar Link
- E Elsevier Scopus Link
- Publons Link
- ORCID Link

Education and Training

Postdoctoral Training

2013 – 2020 **Research Stay, EU** Estonia, Sweden, Germany, Slovakia Spending up to 6 months abroad doing research in the field of price

transmission analysis along food supply chains

2013 – 2015 Summer School on Macroeconomics New Economic School (Russia, Moscow)

In-depth studies on the intermediate, advanced and global macroeconomics

2013 – 2013 Cambridge English Exams

Cambridge ESOL Entry Level Certificate in ESOL International (Coun-

cil of Europe Level B1 in English)

Program for

2008 – 2008 **professional** Institute of professional accountants of Russia(IPAR)

accountants

Advanced training programme for professional accountants

Education

PhD Studies, Ph.D.(The first

2002 – 2005 academic degree "Candidate of Voronezh State Agricultural University

Economic Sciences" in Russia)
Field of study: Agricultural Economics

Ph.D.Dissertation Voronezh State Agricultural University

Prices, pricing and regulation in agricultural sector

1997 – 2002 Master Studies, M.Sc. in Voronezh State Agricultural University Economics

Field of study: Agricultural Economics

Master Theses Voronezh State Agricultural University

Mechanism of the circulating capital control in agricultural enter-

prises and it's improvement ways

Working Experience

2017 – Researcher Voronezh State University of Forestry and Technologies (VSUFT)

Executive secretary at the Editorial Board of the journal "Forestry
Engineering Journal"; research activity, publishing papers in scientific journals, indexed by the international databases, applying for

various scholarships and grants; part-time teaching

2010 – 2017 Assistant Professor

Mobility activity within Erasmus Mundus and DAAD programs; teaching bachelors; doing research within the framework of the Chair research issue "Problems of Russian economy modernisation under

current conditions"

2005 – 2010 **Lecturer** Voronezh State Academy of Forestry and Technologies

Part-time teaching and research activity at the Chair of Economic

Theory

2006 – 2010 Chief Accountant LLC "Business-Center "Etazhi"

Responsible for accounting policy and tax reports

Awards

2020 – 2021 Expansion|research grant

Grant for review article publication funded by Russian Foundation

RFRR

for Basic Research (RFBR) | project №20-110-50002

2020 – 2020 **DAAD scholarship**

Mobility grant within German Exchange Academic Service (DAAD) programme: Germany, Giessen, Justus Liebig University in Giessen

research 3-month stay

2019 – 2020 Research grant ISFE

Grant was funded by the Academician Nikolai Fedorenko International Scientific Foundation of Economic Research (ISFER)| project

№ 2019-124. 2018 – 2018 Immanuel Kant | research programme

Mobility grant within joint DAAD and the Russian Ministry of Science and Higher Education programme №26.12725.2018/12.2: Germany, Giessen, Justus Liebig University in Giessen | research 3-

month stay

Sergei Kharin

Researcher, Agricultural Economics

About Me -

I am a research fellow at VSUFT in Voronezh, Russia. My research interests concentrate on time series econometrics and price transmission analysis with a focus on agricultural markets.

I have been really interested in economics since school. After graduating from school, I entered Voronezh State Agrarian University (VSAU), Faculty of Economics. It was not a random choice. Firstly, I live in the Central-Black Earth Region of Russia. It historically formed as an agrarian one, thanks to its exceptionally favorable and unique soil conditions known all over the world. Secondly, The VSAU economic faculty is the oldest of all economic faculties in Voronezh and the largest training and scientific center of education and research in the Central-Black Earth Region in Russia.

Driving licence

B B1

Hobbies -

- Football (soccer)
- Fishing
- Travelling
- History

Awards

2016 - 2017

2013 – 2014 AURORA

	results grante electronia, thera, electronic electronic in	
	Nitra research 6-month stay)	
2016 – 2016	DAAD scholarship	DAAD
	Mobility grant within DAAD programme: G	ermany, Kiel, Kiel Univer-
	sity (CAU) research 2-month stay	
2014 – 2015	IAMONET-RU	Erasmus Mundus Action 2
	Mobility grant within European Communi	ity Programme: Sweden,
	Uppsala, Swedish University of Agricultur	ral Studies research 6-
	month stay	

National Scholarship programme of Slovak Republic

Mobility grant: Slovakia, Nitra, Slovak University of Agriculture in

SAIA

Erasmus Mundus Action 2

	Mobility grant within European Community Programme: Estonia, Tartu, University of Tartu research 2-month stay	
Notable publications		
2021	Asymmetry in Price Transmission: Evidence from the Wheat-Flour Supply Chain in Russia Kharin S. AGRIS on-line Papers in Economics and Informatics, Vol. 13, No. 3, pp. 67-75.	
2021	Price transmission on agricultural markets: methodological approaches review (in Russ.) Kharin S. Agricultural Science Euro-North-East, Vol. 22(1), pp. 7-20.	
2019	Horizontal Price Transmission on the Russian Dairy Market: Non-linear Approach Kharin S. AGRIS on-line Papers in Economics and Informatics, Vol. 11, No. 3, pp. 45-54.	
2018	Price Transmission Analysis: the Case of Milk Products in Russia Kharin S. AGRIS on-line Papers in Economics and Informatics, Vol. 10, No. 1, pp. 15-23. ☐	

Kharin S., Lajdova Z., Beilik P.

Studies in Agricultural Economics, Vol. 119(3), pp. 148-155.

2015 Vertical price transmission along the diary supply chain in Russia

Kharin S.

2017

Studies in Agricultural Economics, Vol. 117(2), pp. 80-85.